

# Anton Zarubin

Senior Node.js Developer / Team Leader

# **Summary**

About ten years experience in PHP development.

Extensive experience in programming engineering and algorithm development.

Over three years experience in Node.js development.

Strong skills in development and implementation.

Abilities in inventing solutions, algorithms, methods and approaches.

Well skilled in database design and system architecture design.

Strong skill in "Single Page Application" development.

Good attention to details.

Native languages - Russian and Ukrainian. Conversational English.

## **Education**

Graduated from Kharkiv National University of Radio Electronics in 2007, Masters Degree. Kharkiv, Ukraine.

M.S. in Computer Science, major in Computer Data Processing Systems.

#### **Contact**

**L** +380 98 9309333

 ■ anton.zarubin@gmail.com

anton\_zarubin

# **Social**

github.com/zarant77 mm npmjs.com/~zarant77

# Skills

OS/Platform				
#	Windows	18 years	****	
	Linux	12 years	****	
	FreeBSD	2 years	****	
Programming Language				
JS	JavaScript	12 years	****	
豆	HTML	12 years	****	
巨	CSS	12 years	****	
Php	PHP	10 years	****	
	C++	2 years (non-commercial usage)	★★★☆☆	
	Java	1 year (non-commercial usage)	★★☆☆☆	
NoSQL DBMS				
•	MongoDB	1 year	****	
	Couchbase	2 years	****	
	Elasticsearch	2 years	****	

# **Relational DBMS**

Redis

	MS SQL	3 years	****
En Se	MySQL	12 years	****
	PostgreSQL	1 year	★★★☆☆

4 years

# ORM

	Sequelize	3 years	****
MONGÓÓSE.	Mongoose	1 year	****

#### **Tools/Frameworks**

Tools/Frameworks				
(js)	Node.js	4 years	****	
express	Express.js	4 years	****	
hapi	HAPI	Less than a year	****	
<u>u</u>	jQuery	7 years	****	
	Angular	1 year	★★★☆☆	
×	Backbone	Less than a year	★★☆☆☆	
	React	Less than a year	****	
	NW.js	Less than a year	★★★☆☆	
	PhoneGap	Less than a year		
	Cordova	Less than a year		
JADE	Jade	4 years	****	
{less}	LESS	4 years	****	
Sass	SASS	Less than a year		
В	Bootstrap	4 years	****	
Mi	Material-UI	12 years	****	
Team	Collaboration Tools			
•	Git	5 years	****	
:	Subversion	5 years	****	
X,	JIRA	2 years	****	
	Redmine	1 year	****	
心	Target Process	1 year	★★★☆☆	
Network Technologies				
			<b>A A A A</b>	

REST	HTTP(S) REST	5 years	****
	OAuth (1, 2)	1 year	****
<u> </u>	WebSockets	1 year	****

# **Other Tools**

Gule	Gulp	1 year	****
	Grunt	4 years	****
هي	NPM	4 years	****
	Bower	4 years	****
API DOC	ApiDoc	2 years	****
37AF	RAML	1 year	★★★☆☆
<b>({··}</b> )	Swagger	1 year	★★★☆☆
mocha	Mocha	4 years	****
<b>JS</b> Hint	JSHint	2 years	****

## **Experience**

#### 2014 - Present time, Node.js Developer

# Freelancer (Odesk/Upwork) http://upwork.com/

More than year I used to work remotely for MarketWave. (http://www.market-wave.com/) MarketWave is company who provide customer multi-channels management (Phone, Live Chat, etc). Company provide sales support for visitors with key leaders of e-commerce. They was my general clients.

# **Primary Responsibilities:**

Design, develop, test and deploy web applications

Develop appropriate code structures to solve specific tasks according to standards

Fix bugs, troubleshoot and resolve problems

Build flexible data models and seamless integration points Comment code and write documentation using ApiDoc

Code review

## Used technologies and tools:

Platforms: Node.js

Frameworks: Express, Angular, Bootstrap Databases: MS SQL, Couchbase, Elasticsearch

Documentation: ApiDoc QA: Mocha, JSHint

Another tools: Less, Jade, Grunt, Bower, NPM

#### 2012 - 2014, Team Leader / Project Manager

#### **QCoders** http://qcoders.com/

During work in this company I had only one general project which was divided to few small subprojects. InTouch http://intouch.inweb24.us/ InTouch is a email marketing system. Like MailChimp or Mandrill but with an emphasis in network marketing. I'm started this project from scratch. Gradually our team has grown up to 7 developers. It was first experience with Node.js on commercial project.

#### **Primary Responsibilities:**

Project management

Team management (team of seven members)

Estimating and resource planning

Design and development of system architecture

Design and development of source code

Database design and development

GUI design Code review

#### Used technologies and tools:

Platforms: Node.js

Frameworks: Express, Backbone, Bootstrap

Databases: MongoDB Documentation: RAML

QA: Mocha

Another tools: Less, Jade, Grunt, Bower, NPM

#### 2011 - 2012, Senior Software Developer / Team Leader

Quadecco http://quadecco.de/

Development of many projects for outsourcing company using following technologies

## **Primary Responsibilities:**

Team management

Estimating and resource planning

Design and development of system architecture

Design and development of source code

Database design and development

GUI design Code review

## Used technologies and tools:

Platforms: PHP, Javascript, HTML, CSS

Frameworks: YII, Zend Framework, jQuery, Mootools

Databases: MySQL, MSSQL

#### 2009 - 2011, Senior Software Developer / Team Leader

**ZFort Group** http://www.zfort.com.ua/

Development of many projects for outsourcing company using following technologies

#### **Primary Responsibilities:**

Team management

Estimating and resource planning

Design and development of system architecture

Design and development of source code

Database design and development

GUI design Code review

# Used technologies and tools:

Platforms: PHP, Javascript, HTML, CSS

Frameworks: YII, PRADO, Zend Framework, ¡Query

Databases: MySQL

#### 2007 - 2009, Software Developer

**Intetics Co** http://intetics.com/

Development of many projects for outsourcing company using following technologies

#### **Primary Responsibilities:**

Code development

Database development

#### Used technologies and tools:

Platforms: PHP, Javascript, HTML, CSS

Frameworks: jQuery Databases: MySQL

#### 2005 - 2006, Junior Software Developer

**Letwork** http://www.letwork.com/

Development of many projects for outsourcing company using following technologies

# **Primary Responsibilities:**

Code development

Database development

#### Used technologies and tools:

Platforms: PHP, Javascript, HTML, CSS

Databases: MySQL